Guide to the American authors collection, 1832-1956
Department of Special Collections
American authors collection,
1832-1956
Special Collections M0122
4.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Various sources.
Scope and Content
Literary manuscripts and letters of American writers. Autographs, portraits, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets.
Container List
- ADAMS, BRISTOW (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - To Grace M. Webster, 20 Apr. 1932, TLS, 1 p.
- ADE, GEORGE (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - To Harry Leon Wilson, n.d., ACS (autograph only)
- AGER, CAROLUS (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - To [Henry Rushton Fairclough], 28 Jan. 1937, TLS, 1 p.
  - To Ruth, 19 Apr. 1947, TLS, 1 p.
- ALDEN, MRS. ISABELLA MACDONALD (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - To unknown, 24 Mar. 1904, ALS, 2 pp.
    Gift of Harriet F. Buss
- ALDRICH, THOMAS BAILEY (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - To unknown, n.d., AL (autograph & line from poem), 1 p.
- ALMOND, NINA
  SEE J. MITCHEL PILCHER
- ALTROCCHI, JULIA COOLEY
  SEE JANET LEWIS
- ANDERSON, SHERWOOD (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - To Helen Black, n.d., ANS, 1 p.
    #404263
- ANGELO, VALENTI
  SEE WILLIAM SAROYAN
- ARCHER, KATE RENNIE (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Elijah's Sons, n.d., TMs, 2 pp.
  - Voice of China, n.d., TMs, 1 p.
  - War Bonds, n.d., TMs, 1 p.
  - What Shall We Render for These Things, n.d., TMs, 1 p.
  - You, Who Stand By, n.d., TMs, 1 p.
    Source: Mrs. M.C. Sloss
- ASHLEY, MABEL CHARLOTTE
  SEE EDWIN MARKHAM
- ATHERTON, GERTRUDE (MRS. FRANKLIN HORN ATHERTON) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - To Professor [Brenghton?], 15 May n.y., ALS, 2 pp.
  - [Sh Brenghton?] 14 Nov. n.y., ALS, 2 pp.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 15 Jun. 1941,w/env., TLS, 1 p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 27 May 1943,w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 15 Mar. 1947,w/env., TLS, 1 p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 2 Nov. 1947,w/env., ALS, 1 p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 7 Nov. n.y., TLS, 2 pp.
  - To Miss Van Patten, 22 May, n.y., ALS, 2 pp.
    Source: Nathan Van Patten (#532) SEE ALSO CYRIL CLEMENS
- AUSLANDER, JOSEPH (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - To [Mr. & Mrs. M.C. Sloss], P.M. 29 Sept. 1942,w/env., ALS, 1 p.
  - To [Mr. & Mrs. M.C. Sloss], 17 Sept. 1951,w/env., TLS, 1 p.
  - For My New-Born Son, n.d., AMs w/ANS to Max and Hattie [Sloss], 1 p.
  - Prayer Before Dawn, n.d., AMs, 1 p.
    SEE ALSO ELAINE HELMER PARNIE
- BAILEY, MARGERY
  SEE JOHN GOULD FLETCHER
- BAILEY, HAROLD J
  SEE ARCHIBALD MACLEISH
- BAKER, GEORGE B
  SEE WILLIAM SYDNEY PORTER
- BAKER, HOWARD (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ode on the Sea, (p. 2 missing), n.d., TMs, 4 pp.
  - Two Sonnets on Idealistic Beauty, n.d., TMss, 1 p.
- BARCLAY, JULIUS
  SEE GEORGE SANTAYANA
- BARKER, GUY
  SEE A. EDWARD NEWTON
- BARQUIST, MISS
  SEE EDWIN EMERSON
- BEACH, REX
  SEE THEODORE DREISER
- BEETON, MAYSON L.
  SEE CHANNING POLLACK
- BELASCO, DAVID (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Menu from supper in honor of David Belasco, signed, 24 Feb. 1900
- BELL, LILIAN (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - To Mr. Helmer, P.M. 4 Jan. n.y.,w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
    Found in Under Side of Things by Lilian Bell
- BENDER, ALBERT M
  SEE EMMA FRANCES DAWSON
- BENDER, TERRY
  SEE KENNETH PATCHEN
- BENET, STEPHEN VINCENT Autograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- BENET, WILLIAM ROSE (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - To Mrs. [M.C.] Sloss, 4 Dec. 1947,w/env., TLS, 1 p.
- BENNETT, HARRIET (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notebook with handwritten schoolwork and poetry, n.d., 50 pp.
    #379618
- BENNETT, JAMES WILLIAM (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - To Grace Margaret Webster, 16 May 1932, TLS, 1 p.
- BIRD, E.B.
  SEE ELAINE HELMER PARNIE
- BLACK, HELEN
  SEE SHERWOOD ANDERSON
- BLAKE, JAMES VILA (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - In memoriam, 27 Apr. 1925, AMss, 1 p.
    Found in Songs by J.V. Blake, 1902
- BLANCK, JACOB (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - To Raynard C. Swank, 11 Oct. 1955, TNS, 1 p.
    Source: R.C. Swank
- BLAND, HENRY MEADE (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - correspondence with Roland F. Eberhart, 12 Sept. 1914-6 Apr. 1927, 29 ALS
    Source: Roland F. Eberhart (#1237-1265)
  - The Backlog Speaks, n.d., TMss (poem), 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Gift of Alma L. Williams
  - A Ballade of Autumn, n.d., TMs (poem), 1 p.
  - By Joaquin Sedgies, TMsS (poem), 1 p.
  - Triolet, 19 Aug. 1926, TMsS, 1 p.
    Source: Roland F. Eberhart
    (#1253, 1236) SEE ALSO EDWIN MARKHAM
- BLISS
  SEE BRET HARTE
- BLIVEN, BRUCE (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - To Harold Davis, 26 May 1923, TLS, 1 p.
  - To R.C. Swank, 13 Sept. 1956, TLS, 1 p.
- BOGGS, TOM (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - For Christmas For Willard, n.d., poem, TMsS, 1 p.
    Found in Arenas by Tom Boggs, 1943
- BONAVIA, E (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - To Mrs. [Thimm?], 28 Sept. 1894, ALS, 4 pp.
  - To Mrs. [Thimm?], 28 Jun. 1899, ALS, 6 pp.
- BOWER, ROBERT J. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - A Statute for the International City of Tangier, Nov. 1946, TMs, 24 pp.
  - Photocopy of an article by Maxwell Blake, Oct. 1942, TMs, 2 pp.
  - Outline for A Statute... n.d., 3 pp., TMs
- BRADFORD, GAMALIEL (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - To Prof. U.B. Phillips, 11 Aug. 1913, TLS, 4 pp.
  - To Prof. U.B. Phillips, 15 Aug. 1913, TLS, 2 pp.
  - To Prof. U.B. Phillips, 18 Aug. 1913, TLS, 6 pp.
- BRANDEN, PAUL MAERKER (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - From Ernst Hanfstangl, 4 Apr. 1932, photocopy ALS, 3 pp.
  - From Edward M. House, 13 Sept. 1933, TLS, 1 p.
  - From David Starr Jordan, 26 Sept. 1918-29 Sept. 1923, 6 pp., TLS
  - From William M. King, 20 July 1918-23 Sept. 1918, 3 TLS, 3 pp.
  - From John J. Pershing, 2 July 1932, photocopy TLS, 1 p.
  - From T.V. Ranck, 20 Sept. 1933, TL, 1 p.
  - From Unknown (signature unclear), n.d., ANS, 1 p.
  - From T.V. Ranck to Henry P. Burton, 29 Mar. 1932, photocopy TLS, 1 p.
    Gift of Mrs. Elsa Branden
    Miscellaneous newsclippings regarding interview with Hitler, Polish corridor, etc.
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 11 Sept. 1918 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- BRANDT, CARL
  SEE RICHARD MARTIN STERN
- BREMER, ANNA M
  SEE INEZ HAYNES IRWIN
- BRIDGE, HORATIO
  SEE JULIAN HAWIHORNE
- BROOKS, JUANITA (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - To Ralph Hansen, 2 Feb. 1970,w/env., TLS, 1 p.
    Gift of Ralph Hansen
- BROOKS, VAN WYCK (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - To [Ray Lyman] Wilbur, 6 Aug. 1940, TLS
  - From R.L. Wilbur, 26 Sept. 1940, TLC
    Gift of R.L. Wilbur (#1444)
- BROUGHTON, MR.
  SEE CHARLES CALDWELL DOBIE
- BROWN, MRS. HUGH (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - To the Janitor, n.d., TMs (poem), 2 pp.
- BRYANT, WILLIAM CULLEN (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - To Rev. R.C. Waterston, 16 Aug. 1860, ALS, 3 pp.
  - To unknown, 11 Jan. 1873, ANS, 1 p.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins (#528)
- BUCK, PEARL S. (MRS. RICHARD J. WALSH) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - To [M.C.] Sloss, 23 Nov. 1940, TNS, 1 p.
    Source: Mrs. M.C. Sloss[?]
  - To Ray Lyman Wilbur, 13 Jan. 1941, TLS, 1 p.
    Gift of Ray Lyman Wilbur (#1446)
- BURGESS, GELETT (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Mrs. Woodworth Northey Murray, calling card
  - From Inez Haynes Irwin to Mrs. Wm. Murray, 15 Dec. 1947,regarding The Lark, ALS, 1 p.
  - From Inez Haynes Irwin to Mrs. Wm. Murray, 3 Jan. 1947 [should be 1948],regarding The Lark, ALS, 1 p.
    SEE ALSO THEODORE DREISER
  - Goops, 1913-14, 17 TMs proof sheets [never published], 17 pp. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Pencil sketches, n.d., 5 pp.
  - Social Sinners, 1928, 11 cartoons clipped from magazines and advance proof copies
  - Suicide, 1910, TMsS, 12 pp.
    Gift of Spencer Bickerton
- BURNETT, FRANCES HODGSON 1902, Autograph (Box 1, Folder 35)
- BURTON, JOHN (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 28 Jan. 1932w/env., TLS, 1 p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 22 May 1932w/env., TLS, 1 p.
- BURTON, HENRY P
  SEE PAUL MAERKER BRANDEN
- BYNNER, WITTER (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - To Fred O'Brien, 9 Apr. 1931, TLS, 1 p.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins
  - Persistence of Poetry, n.d., TMs (essay) with hand corrections, 11 pp. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Sapphics to Celia, Jan 1922, TMsS (poem) with hand corrections, 3 pp.
    Gift of A.M. Bender
- CALKINS, EARNEST ELMO
- CARPENTER, THOMAS R
  SEE FRANCES MARION CRAWFORD
- CARTER, JIMMY
  SEE CYRIL CLEMENS
- CHAMBERS, ROBERT W
  SEE ELAINE HEIMER PARNIE
- CHANDLER, HARRY
- CHATTO, MR.
- CLEMENS
  SEE NELLIE V. SANCHEZ
- CLEMENS, CYRIL (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE
    - From Gertrude Atherton, 4 May 1937, APCS, 1 p.
    - From Gertrude Atherton, 25 Jan [1940], ALS, 1 p.
    - From Gertrude Atherton, 21 Sept. 1946, APCS, 1 p.
    - From Jimmy Carter, 26 Sept. 1976, TLS (xerox), 1 p.
    - From Jimmy Carter, 10 Jan. 1977, TLS (xerox), 1 p.
    - From Harry Chandler, 5 June 1937, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Jean Cocteau, Aug. 1958, photocopy ANS plus sketch, 1 p.
    - From Bernard Devoto, 28 Oct. 1935w/env., ALS, 1 p.
    - From Charles C. Dobie, 11 Feb. 1936, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Charles C. Dobie, 26 Mar. 1936, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Sheridan Downey, 1 Dec. 1948, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Mrs. George A. Duerr, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Thomas A. Edison, 10 Jan. 1927, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Albert Einstein, 2 Feb. 1940, photocopy TLS, 1 p.
    - From Sara Bard Field, 17 June 1938, APCS, 1 p.
    - From W.R. Gillis, 31 Dec. 1928w/env., APCS, 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - From Henry David Gray, 23 Mar 1939, TLS, 1 p.
    - From James Norman Hall, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Ernest Hemingway, 6 Apr. 1930, ALS, 1 p.
    - From James Hopper, n.d., ALS, 1 p.
    - From Rupert Hughes, 14 Mar. 1949, ALS, 1 p.
    - From Wallace Irwin, 3 Dec. 1935, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Wallace Irwin, 13 Mar. 1948w/env., TLS, 1 p.
    - From Wallace Irwin, 18 Mar. 1952, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Wallace Irwin, 6 Feb. 1955, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Wallace Irwin, 12 Mar. 1957, TLS w/handwritten postscript
    - From Mrs. Wallace Irwin, n.d., ANS, 1 p.
    - Robinson Jeffers, George Sterling, 1941, xerox of AMsS
    - From R. Jeffers, proof of A Great Man in our Time, 1954,w/env.
    - From Una Jeffers, 25 Aug. 1936, ALS, 1 p.
    - From Una Jeffers, 16 Sept. 1941, APCS, 1 p.
    - From Una Jeffers, 5 Mar. 1945, APCS, 1 p.
    - From Hiram Johnson, 18 Feb. 1935, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Merle Johnson, 21 Apr. 1932, APCS, 1 p.
    - From David Starr Jordan, 9 Feb. 1929w/env., TLS, 1 p.
    - From John F. Kennedy, 25 Dec. 1961, photocopy ANS, 1 p.
    - From Goodwin J. Knight, 8 Apr. 1954, TLS, 1 p.
    - William F. Knowland, 4 Apr. 1957, TLS, 1 p.
    - C. Day Lewis, 15 Mar. 1968, photocopy TNS, 1 p.
    - From Charmian Kittredge London, 4 Aug. 1943, TPCS
    - From Mabel Dodge Luhan, 15 Apr. [1938]w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
    - From Walt Mason, 28 June 1935, TLS, 1 p.
    - From F.O. Matthiessen, 12 Nov. 1942, TLS, 1 p.
    - Walter F. Mondale, 9 Jan. 1975, photocopy TLS, 1 p.
    - From Benito Mussolini, 3 Nov. 1930, photocopy ALS, 1 p.
    - From J.H. Nash, 29 Aug. 1930, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Bliss Perry, 29 Aug. [1942], APCS, 1 p.
    - From Cale Young Rice, 13 June 1940, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Constance Rourke, Dec. 1929, TLS, 3 pp.
    - From Constance Rourke, 1 Mar. 1936, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Constance Rourke, 1 June 1940, TLS, 1 p.
    - To Carl Sandburg, P.M. 5 Mar. 1950with pencilled one line reply from CS written on it, n.d.,w/env., TPGS, 1 p.
    - From George Bernard Shaw, 28 Nov. 1941, photocopy ANS, 1 p.
    - From George Bernard Shaw, 10 May, 1941, photocopy ANS, 1 p.
    - From Upton Sinclair, 16 Mar. 1938, TNS, 1 p.
    - From Wallace Stegner, 7 Apr. 1953, TLS, 1 p.
    - From John Steinbeck, 15 Sept. 1941, TLS. 1 p.
    - From J.E. Wallace Sterling, 22 May 1957, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Winifred Stilwell, 7 July 1954, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Nathan Van Patten, 10 Apr. 1937, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Nathan Van Patten, 12 May 1949, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Nathan Van Patten, 23 May 1954, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Nathan Van Patten, 16 Apr. 1955, ALS, 1 p.
    - From Stewart Edward White, 15 June 1938, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Ray Lyman Wilbur, 24 May 1943, TLS, 1 p.
    - From Charles Erskine Scott Wood, 2 Sept. 1928, ANS
    - From Charles Erskine Scott Wood, 29 May 1932, ALS, 1 p.
    - From William Butler Yeats, 2 June n.y., photocopy ALS, 1 p.
    - To Mr. Barclay, 10 Mar. 1962, TLS, 1 p.
    - To Danziger [Adolphe De Castro], 21 Aug. 1900, photocopy ALS, 5 pp.
      Gift of Cyril Clemens SEE ALSO UPTON SINCLAIR
- CLEMENS, MRS. JAMES
  SEE SAMUEL CLEMENS
- CLEMENS, SAMUEL (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - To Mrs. James Clemens, 16 Oct. 1906, ALS photocopy, 2 pp.
    Gift of Cyril Clemens
  - To Mrs. Stanford, Apr. 1910, ANS, 1 p.
  - To Charles Warren Stoddar, 15 Dec. 1902, APCS, 1 p.
  - 2 autographs, to unknown, n.d.
  - To Fuller, n.d., ALS, 1 p., Photo of S.C. ALS, 6 1/4" x 4 1/2"
- COBB, MARGARET S.
  SEE ROBINSON JEFFERS
- COCTEAU, JEAN
- COGSWELL
  SEE NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE
- COOLBRITH, INA DONNA (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 2 May 1922, ALS, 1 p.
    Source: Gift of Mrs. Sloss?
  - Unheeded, 27 Feb. 1911, AMsS (poem) 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Source: Mrs. Sloss[?], #390023
  - Life of Ina Donna Coolbirth, n.d., AMs, 18 pp.
- COOLIDGE, EDWIN (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - To Emma Frances Dawson, n.d., AMsS (poem), 1 p.
    Source: A.M. Bender (#11)
- COOLIDGE, MARY ROBERTS (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - To Miss Webster, 20 Apr. 1932, TLS, 1 p.
- CRAIG, FLORENCE
  SEE HAMLIN GARLAND
- CRAIG, GORDON
- CRAWFORD, FRANCES MARION (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Thomas P. Carpenter to [Nathan] Van Patten, 3 Jan. 1945,concerns an autograph of F.M. Crawford which is not enclosed., TLS, 1 p.
    Source: T.P. Carpenter
- CREEL, GEORGE (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Tom Paine-Liberty Bell, TMs w/hand corrections, n.d., 121 pp.
    Gift of George Creel
- CROCKETT, S.A.
- CUMMINGS, E.E.
  SEE EZRA POUND
- CUNNINGHAM, J.V. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - To the Stanford English Club, 31 May 1939, TLS, 2 pp.
- CURRAN
  SEE EDWARD EVERETT HALE
- CURTIS, GEORGE WILLIAM (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - To unknown, 9 Nov. 1869, ALS, 1 p.
- DANA, JULIAN (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - To Miss Hitchcock, 22 Jan. 1937, TLS, 1 p.
  - To Miss Hitchcock, 10 Mar. 1937, TLS, 1 p.
- DANIELS, JOSEPHUS
  SEE WILLIAM KIMBERLEY PALMER
- DANZIGER, ADOLPHE DE CASTRO
- DARLINGTON, HANNAHILL
  SEE JOHN G. WHITTIER
- DAVIS, HAROLD
  SEE BRUCE BLIVEN
- DAVIS, HORACE (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - To [Horace Davis], from W.J. Rolfe, 26 Dec. 1889, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shakespeare's Sonnets, n.d., AMs, 300 pp.
    Gift of Horace Davis [?]
  - Shakespeare's Sonnets, n.d., AMs bound notebook, 359 pp. (Oversize OS1, Folder 1)
    Gift of Horace Davis (#263741)
- DAWSON, EMMA FRANCES (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - To Albert M. Bender, P.M. 9 Mar. 1921,w/env., ACS, 4 pp.
  - To Albert M. Bender, 13 Jan. 1923w/env., ACS, 2 pp.
    (Gift of A.M. Bender #404262, 390898)
  - In the Twinkling of An Eye, n.d., AMsS (poem), 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Source: A.M. Bender (#10) SEE ALSO EDWIN COOLIDGE
- DEVINNE, THEO L.
- DEVOTO, BERNARD
- DILLON, RICHARD (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - To Ralph Hansen, 3 Feb. 1972, APCI, 1 p.
    Source: Ralph Hansen
- DOBIE, CHARLES CALDWELL (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - To Mr. Broughton, 3 May 1934, ALS, 1 p.
    SEE ALSO CYRIL CLEMENS
- DOWNEY, SHERIDAN
- DREISER, THEODORE (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - From Rex Beach, 26 Apr. 1923, TL (transcription), 1 p.
  - To Rex Beach, 5 May 1923, TLS, 2 pp.
  - To Gelett Burgess, n.d., TL, 4 pp.
  - To Holmes Book Company, 27 Apr. 1926w/env., TLS, 1 p.
  - To [George K.] Hyde, 9 Mar. 1928w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
  - To [George K.] Hyde, 1 May 1928w/env., TLS, 1 p.
  - From Charles Timothy Jewett, 26 Oct. 1929, TL (carbon) 1 p.
  - To Mr. Woodberry, 10 Sept. 1921, TLS, 1 p.
  - To unknown, 27 July 1921(Gelber collection), TLS, 1 p.
  - Newsclipping re: Theodore & Paul Dreiser, n.d.Gelber collection [?]
- DUEN, MRS. GEORGE A.
- DUYCKINK, EVERT AUGUSTUS (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - To [Edward E.] Hale, n.d., ALS, 2 pp.
    Gift of Dr. Lorie Tarshis SEE ALSO NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE, FRANKLIN BENJAMIN SANBORN
- EBERHART, ROLAND
  SEE HENRY MEADE BLAND
- EDISON, THOMAS A.
- EINSTEIN, ALBERT
- ELKINS, KATE FELTON
  SEE RUTH ELVISH MANTY, CARLOTTA MONTEREY O'NEILL, EUGENE O'NEILL
- ELLIS, WILLIAM
- EMERSON, EDWIN (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - To Miss Garquist, 1953, ALS, 3 pp.
    Gift of E. Emerson
- EMERSON, RALPH WALDO (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - To Mr. Alfred Wilkinson, 31 Jan. 1854, ALS, 3 pp.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins (#56)
  - From a lecture written in England, [1842-43], AMs, 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Gift of Mrs. Y. Frederick Dutton Given to Mrs. Dutton by Edward Waldo Emerson
- ERSKINE, JOHN 1929, Autograph (Box 2, Folder 12)
- FAIRCLOUGH, HENRY RUSHTON
  SEE CAROLUS AGER
- FICKE, ARTHUR DAVISON (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Great Poetry is not necessarily born...!, AMsS, 1 p.
  - Big Bill Thompson, (2nd version, for Competition 13), TMs 1 p.
  - Biggest Bill Thompson, (3rd version, for Competition 13), TMs 1 p.
  - Mayor Bill Thompson (1st version, for Competition 13), TMs 1 p.
  - U.S. Proposes to Ban Submarines, AMs, 1 p.
  - Newsclippings regarding Competition no. 13 for sonnets, Saturday Review
    Gift of Albert M. Bender
- FIELD, CHARLES K. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - To My dear friend, 6 June 1899, TLS, 1 p.
  - To Mrs. Stanford, 23 May 1899, AMsS, 2 pp.
- FIELD, EUGENE (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - To Mr. Gray, 7 Dec. 1893, ALS, 1 p.
    Found in Tribute in Memory of Mrs. Ruth C. Gray, by Eugene Field, PS 1667.T85 1895
- FIELD, RACHEL [PEDERSON, RACHEL FIELD] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 31 May 1939, ALS, 1 p.
- FIELD, SARA BARD
  SEE CYRIL CLEMENS, CHARLES ERSKINE SCOTT WOOD
- FISHER, DOROTHY CANFIELD (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - To My dear Helen, 12 June n.y., TLS, 1 p.
    Found in Home Fires in France, by Dorothy Canfield.
  - Newsclipping, portrait of Dorothy Canfield, n.d.
- FLETCHER, JOHN GOULD (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - To Margery Bailey, 20 Oct. [1940],w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
    Gift of Dr. Margery Bailey. (#1604)
  - To Mrs. [Max] Sloss, 26 Oct. 1945w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
  - To Mrs. [Max] Sloss, 16 May 1946w/env., ALS, 3 pp.
  - To Mrs. [Max] Sloss, 6-7 July 1946w/env., ALS, 2 pp.
  - Newsclipping, regarding Herbert Elwell's Lincoln wins Paderewski award, 17 Mar. 1946
- FRANKLIN, H. BRUCE (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - From H. Bruce Franklin to Stanford Libraries, 20 Mar. 1967, ANS
  - The Confidence Man: His Masquerade, by Herman Melville, edited with an introduction and annotation by H. Bruce Franklin., TMs with hand corrections, 300 pp.
    Gift of H. Bruce Franklin
- FRANKLIN, LENORE
  SEE UNA JEFFERS, JOHN O'SHEA
- FULLER
- FULLER, MARGARET
  SEE HENRY & ALINE HARLAND
- FULLER, MRS. W.P., JR.
- GALE, COL. CHARLES W.
- GARLAND, HAMLIN (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - To Miss (Florence) Craig, 18 Mar. n.y., ALS, 1 p.
    Gift of Miss Florence Craig (#953)
- GARVIN, MISS
- GELBER, LEON
  SEE JOHN STEINBECK, UNA JEFFERS
- GEORGIANA
  SEE SARAH MARGARET FULLER OSSOLI
- GILDER, MR.
  SEE JOEL CHANDLER HARRIS
- GILLIS, W.R.
- GRABAU, MARY ANTIN (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - To Mr. & Mrs. Max Sloss, printed invitation to High School of Practical Arts order of exercises, signed, w/env.
- GREELEY, HORACE (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - To Dear Sir, 3 Mar. 1871, ALS, 1 p.
    Gift of Mr. Hugh Wiley (#1022)
  - To Dear Sir, 16 June [?] 1872, ALS, 1 p.
- GORHAM, CHARLES
  SEE JESSAMYN WEST MCPHERSON, WILLIAM SAROYAN
- GOSSE, EDMUND
- GRAY, MR.
  SEE EUGENE FIELD
- GRAY, HENRY DAVID
- GUEST, EDGAR A. 25 Dec. 1916, Autograph (Box 2, Folder 23)
- HALBERSTAM, DAVID (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - To Mr. (Fred C.) Lynden, Stanford University Libraries, 10 July 1973, ALS, 1 p.
- HALE, EDWARD EVERETT (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - To Miss Curran, 8 May 1890, ALS, 1 p.
    Bequest of Dr. C.D. Mosher (#3312)
  - To Dear Friend, 25 June 1898, ALS, 1 p.
    Gift of Helen Wright Dutton
  - To Mr. Howland, 6 Nov. 1897, ALS, 1 p.
    Found in The Man Without a Country, by Edw. E. Hale, Boston, Little, Brown, 1906
  - To [Mr. Kuinan?], 9 Oct. 1908, ALS, 1 p.
    Gift of Professor William Hawley Davis SEE ALSO EVERT KUYCKINK
- HALL, JAMES NORMAN
- HANFSTANGL, ERNST
- HANSEN, RALPH
  SEE JUANITA BROOKS, RICHARD DILLON
- HARLAND, HENRY & ALINE (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - From [Margaret Fuller?], 26 Nov. 1917, TL with Ms portion, 1 p.
  - From Margaret Fuller, 6 Dec. 1917, TL, 1 p.
  - To Miss Fuller, 5 July 1919, ALS, 1 p.
  - To Miss Fuller, PM 22 July 1919,w/env., ANS, 1 p.
  - To Miss Fuller, 31 Dec. 1919,w/env., ALS, 1 p.
  - From [Margaret Fuller?], 17 Jan. 1920, TL, 3 pp.
  - To Miss Fuller, 9 Mar. 1920,w/env., ALS, 3 p.
  - From [Margaret Fuller?], 12 May 1920, TL, 1 p.
  - To [?], n.d., ANS fragment, 1 p.
  - From [?] to Margaret Fuller, 26 Jan. 1919re: AH, ANS, 1 p.
  - From Louise C. Howe, ND,regarding AH & HH, TMs, 1 p.
  - To Col. Charles W. Gale from Margaret Fuller, 24 Jan. 1919regarding HH, TLS, 1 p.
  - Receipt and coupons, sale of Erie Railroad Co. bonds
  - From Donald A. Roberts to Louise C. Howe, 22 July 1927regarding HH, TLS, 1 p.
  - From Theodore K. McCarthy to Mrs. AJ Mix, 23 Jan. 1936regarding AH, TLS, 1 p.
  - To Mrs. Mix from Margaret Fuller, 5 Feb. 1947.Ms enclosure, TLS, 2 pp.
  - To Katherine Mix from Louise C. Howe, 2 Mar. 1980regarding AH, TLS, 4 pp.
  - Handwritten genealogical notes, 1 p.
  - Handwritten notes regarding AH, unsigned, 3 pp.
  - Miss Louise Howe, TMs, regarding HH & AH, n.d., 15 pp.
  - 2 envelopes 26 Jan. 1919, 23 Nov. 19[19]
    Gift of K.L. Mix
  - Harland estate in Norwich, CT, 4 photographs (Box 2, Folder 27)
- HARPER, JOSEPH W.
- HARRIS, FRANK (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - To Frederick O'Brien, 19 July 1920, TLS, 1 p.
- HARRIS, JOEL CHANDLER (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - To Mr. Gilder, 24 Sept. 1901, ALS, 1 p.
    Source: Mrs. K. F. Elkins
  - To Mr. Gilder, 9 Dec. n.y., ALS, 1 p.
- HARTE, BRET (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - To Bliss, 8 June 1875, ALS, 1 p.
  - To Mssrs. Chatto & Windus, 23 Feb. 1880, ALS, 1 p.
    Source: Duschnes
  - To Gentlemen [James R. Osgood & Co.], 30 May 1870, ALS, 1 p.
  - To Lady Lindsay, n.d., ALS. 1 p., Photo of BH 3 1/2" x 5 1/2"
    Autograph, 13 June 1873 Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins
- HARTMANN, SADAKICHI (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Drifting Flowers of the Sea and Other Poems, 1904.Photo of author on cover, TMsS, 21 pp.
- HAWTHORNE, JULIAN (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - To Laurence, 3 May 1887, ALS, 1p.
  - To Margaret Watson, 20 Feb. 1932,regarding The Journal of an African Cruise, by Horatio Bridge., TLS, 1p.
- HAWTHORNE, NATHANIEL (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - To [Evert Augustus Duyckink], 15 June 1852,regarding purchase of house belonging to Bronson Alcott., photocopy of ALS, 2pp.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins (original with Miss Margaret Lathrop)
  - Check for $34.89 to L. Reynolds, 1832, autograph
  - About Warwick, AMs, p. 3 and 4, 2pp. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Review of The Supernaturalism of New England by J.G. Whittier, photocopy AMsS, 3p.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins with letter to [surveyor's office], [?] Apr. 1847
  - George S. Hillard to Cogswell, re: NH, ALS, 1p.
- HAY, JOHN
  SEE EDMUND C. STEDMAN
- HAYNES, INEZ
  SEE GELETT BURGESS
- HAYWARD, REV. WILLIAM C.
  SEE HJAIMARN R. HOLAND
- HECHT, MRS.
  SEE JULIA WARD HOWE
- HEINEMANN, WILLIAM
  SEE UPTON SINCLAIR
- HELMER
  SEE LILIAN BELL
- HELMER, HAROLD
- HEMINGWAY, ERNEST (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - #71 out of 93 facsimile foundry proofs printed of The Bastard Sheet. [1931], 1p.
    Source: Kirgo Books, New York SEE ALSO CYRIL CLEMENS
- HENDEY, K
  SEE RICHARD HOVEY
- HENRY. O.
  SEE PORTER, WILLIAM SYDNEY
- HEWLETT, MAURICE
- HILLARD, GEORGE S
- HITCHCOCK
  SEE JULIAN DANA
- HOLAND, HJAIMAN R. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - To Rev. William C. Hayward, 18 May 1940, ALS, 2pp.
  - To Rev. William C. Hayward, 31 May 1940, ALS, 1p.
- HOLLIDAY, ROBERT CORTES
- HOLMES, BROOK COMPANY
- HOLMES, OLIVER W. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - To [?], 7 July 1859, ALS, 1p.
  - To Martin Steele, 8 Feb. 1866, ANS, 1p.
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins Autograph, 22 May 1889
- HOPPER, JAMES
- HORATIO AND GLORIA
- HOUSE, EDWARD M.
- HOVEY, HENRIETTA
  SEE HORACE TRAUBEL
- HOVEY, HENRIETTA (MRS. RICHARD) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - To Dearest, July 1893, ALS, 1p.
  - To Mrs. Hovey from K. Hendey, 4 Feb. 1903, ALS, 1p.
  - To Maynard, ND.Also signed by Henrietta Hovey, ALS, 3pp.
    Source: Sigurd Russell
  - Hafiz, n.d., AMs, 1p. (Box 2, Folder 39)